

**INFO** 

#### Date and place of birth

15.04.1986 Romania

#### Permit

Swiss B-Permit

#### **Status**

Married

#### **CONTACT**

#### Address

Basel, Switzerland

#### E-mail

melania.marcian@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/melania-petcu

# Melania Elena Petcu

Software Developer

## Summary

I am an experienced software developer and skilled requirements analyst, with a demonstrated history of working in information technology. My user-centered proclivity, that was highly appreciated in my role as Product Owner and customer support, led me to an active interest in UX design, which is supported by my continuously practiced problem-solving skills.

## **Key Skills**

## > Efficiency

Filling at the same time the roles of Developer, Customer Support specialist and Product Owner, I demonstrated my competency in performance, focus, prioritization and time management.

## > Empathy

As a Customer Support specialist and Product Owner, I connected with both customers and clients individually and established a cordial, trustworthy and professional relationship with each of them.

#### Adaptability

As a Customer Support specialist, the issues raised by the customers were usually very different from one another and they needed specific actions into solving or answering them.

#### ➤ Team-player & Collaborator

As Product Owner and developer, I consistently collaborated with team leads, project managers and software engineers of auxiliary products, integrated with our own, as well as with representatives of other departments (e.g. Integration, Master data, BI) and system architects.

#### > Problem solver

As a developer, I performed thorough investigative and analytical work of every new request, prior to development.

As Product Owner, I gained broader strategic thinking, considering also the whole picture while working through the details.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Technical

Adobe XD

Balsamiq

Dreamweaver

CSS

HTML

XMI

Oracle APEX

Oracle PL/SQL

## **Industry**

Requirements Analysis

Database Design

#### CERTIFICATIONS

#### UI / UX Design Specialization

California Institute of the Arts

#### **Oracle Database Certified Expert**

Oracle

#### **Oracle Developer Certified Associate**

Oracle

## **Knowledge and Interests**

Languages Romanian (mother tongue)

> English (fluent) French (basic)

German (basic)

Online courses UI / UX Design

> A 4-course specialization by California Institute of the Arts on Coursera.

**User Experience Design Essentials** 

A 10.5 hours course by Daniel Scott on

Skillshare.

**UX Design Fundamentals** 

A 12 hours course by Joe Natoli on Skillshare.

UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy,

Design, Development

A 23.5 hours course by Joe Natoli on Udemy

## Education

10/2005 - 07/2008 Academy of Economic Studies

Bucharest, Romania > Specialization: Informatics, Economics

"Mihai Viteazul" National College 09/2001 - 07/2005

Ploiești, Romania

Specialization: Informatics

## Experience

02/2020 - present Basel, Switzerland

## **DIGITAL SOLUTIONS Switzerland**

Oracle Full Stack Developer

#### Responsibilities:

- Development of web based applications in APEX framework
- Development of PL/SQL stored procedures in Oracle Database

07/2014 - 07/2019

Bucharest, Romania

#### METRO SYSTEMS Romania

Product Owner & Full Stack Developer

#### Responsibilities as Product Owner:

- Customer liaison and first person of contact in any of the product's international branches
- Create User Stories and acceptance criteria for Product Backlog and prioritise tasks
- Map out project dependencies to inform the necessary sequence of development
- Prepare end-user documentation/manuals, that help users interact with the product effectively
- Give user and client presentations / show and tell sessions

# Responsibilities as Customer Support s pecialist:

- > Respond promptly to customer inquiries
- Communicate with customers through various channels
- Acknowledge and resolve customer complaints

# Responsibilities as Full Stack Oracle Developer:

- Development of web based applications in APEX framework
- Development of PL/SQL stored procedures in Oracle Database

07/2012 - 07/2014

Bucharest, Romania

IBM Romania

Global Delivery Center

Oracle PL/SQL Developer

## Responsibilities:

Development of PL/SQL stored procedures in Oracle database

06/2007 - 07/2012

Bucharest, Romania

Kepler-Rominfo

Requirements Analyst & Oracle PL/SQL Developer

#### Responsibilities as Requirements Analyst:

- ➤ Gather requirements from clients and validate them by cross-reference
- Document requirements by creating functional and technical specifications that are used further for development